So, I have the subject and objective set for my presentation
Now here is my 10-page script
What? Ten pages? Without any bullet points?
What is the structure of your presentation?
Yes, before you write the full script,
it’s better to outline the structure of your presentation.
What’s the structure of a presentation?
Basically, it’s the arrangement of the parts
in your presentation
Divide the presentation into several parts
and state the main points in each part
Oh, so it will be more organized and easier to understand?
Usually the structure of a presentation consists of three parts
an introduction, a body and a closing
You already know how to make the introduction
Yes. It includes welcoming and introducing your name, title and job
You also know how to introduce the subject
and objectives of your presentation
And now we’re moving to the second part of the presentation’s structure
the body.
First, begin with an overview
It provides general information about the presentation
but not the details
In other words
an overview is a short description of the whole presentation
Right. After the overview
establish the content of the presentation
You should decide on the main points and address them separately
So, if I have three main points, I could say
“First, I’ll be looking at…, second…, and third…“
You can also number the points under the whole structure
Today I will divide my presentation into three main points
Point one deals with…  point two…  and point three...
Or you could say, I will begin with….
Then I’ll move to.... and I’ll end with....
Using this structure
there could be sub points that support the main point
so the overall structure is well-developed and easy to follow
After the body comes the closing
It should give the presentation a summary or a conclusion
Outlining the structure helps lay a solid foundation
before you write the full script
It’s kind of like drawing a blueprint for a house, right?
First, you decide on how many floors are in the house
and then how many rooms are on one floor
Last, you plan and work on //the details inside of the structure
Right. Now what are you going to do with your 10-page script?
Good question! I can still use it later
But, first things first
I will work on outlining the structure right now